# **CURRICULUM VITæ - JOÃO GALEGO**

I am a certified Physics nerd and an amateur forensic scientist with a keen interest in solving interesting and demanding problems. Over the years, I've worked as a data analyst, software tester, test automation engineer, DevOps engineer and ML consultant for several companies, in areas ranging from market research to fiber optic telecommunications and mobility. Currently, I work as a DevOps engineer and ML consultant at the Siemens Lisbon Tech Hub, while pursuing a PhD degree in Cognitive Science at Universidade de Lisboa. My research focuses on the application of ML algorithms to improve the performance of EEG-based brain-computer interfaces.

#### **EDUCATION**

Universidade de Lisboa PhD Cognitive Science	2017 - Present
Instituto Superior de Ciências Sociais e Políticas  PgD Forensic Studies	2016 – 2017
Instituto Superior Técnico MSc Physics	2008 - 2013
Professional Experience	
Siemens DevOps Engineer / ML Consultant	2019 - Present
Innowave DevOps Engineer	2017 – 2019
Coriant Test Automation Engineer	2014 - 2017
CERTIFICATIONS	

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure, Google Cloud

Languages: C/C++, Go, Java, MATLAB, Python, Ruby

Tools: Ansible, Docker, Packer, Terraform

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

#### Al@Sustainability Hackathon - Technical Excellence (Team Mobility)

Siemens

# **Junior Research Scholarship**

Fundação para a Ciência e Tecnologia (FCT)

### Associate Android Developer Fast Track Program Scholarship

Google/Udacity

## LANGUAGES

Deutsch (elementary proficiency), English (full professional proficiency), Español (professional working proficiency), Français (professional working proficiency), Italiano (elementary proficiency), Português (native)